Guide to the Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers, 1831-1970 SC.1958.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers
1831-1994
1831-1970
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Rinehart, Mary Roberts
SC.1958.03
14 Linear Feet (34 boxes)
Mary Roberts Rinehart (1876-1958) was a popular and prolific American author in the first half of the 20th century. Best known for her mysteries, Rinehart published poems, short stories, plays, articles, essays, memoirs, romances, and novels. Some of her works were adapted for stage, film, radio, and television. The Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers document her career as a writer, her life, her family, and her travels and activities. Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Biography
Mary Roberts Rinehart (née Mary Ella Roberts) was born in 1876 and raised in Allegheny City, Pennsylvania, now the North Side of Pittsburgh. Mary and her parents, Thomas (Tom) and Cornelia Roberts, lived with Tom's mother and siblings until Mary's sister Olive was born. At 17, Rinehart enrolled in the Pittsburgh Homeopathic School for Nurses. She drew on her experiences nursing patients in the Pittsburgh Homeopathic Hospital in some of her writing. In 1896, shortly after her graduation from nursing school, she married Stanley Marshall Rinehart, a young doctor. In their house in Allegheny City, Mary Roberts Rinehart managed the household, assisted with Dr. Rinehart's medical practice, and began raising their family of three sons: Stanley Marshall Rinehart Jr., born 1897, Alan Gillespie Rinehart, born 1900, and Frederick "Ted" Roberts Rinehart, born 1902.
In the early 1900's, Rinehart began writing in earnest as a way to contribute to the family's income. The poems and short stories of her early career were published in magazines such as Munsey's Magazine and The All-Story. Her first book, The Circular Staircase, was published in 1908. As her popularity grew so did the family's income, and they moved to a large house in Glen Osborne, Pennsylvania around 1912. In early 1915, Rinehart asked her Saturday Evening Post editor to send her to Europe to report on World War I prior to U.S. involvement. Rinehart toured the Belgian front and interviewed Albert I, King of the Belgians, and Queen Mary of England at a time when very few journalists were granted such access. Rinehart returned to Europe in 1918 to report on the war to the War Department and was in Paris on November 11 when the armistice ended the war.
The Rineharts moved to Washington, D.C. during the winter of 1921-22 when Dr. Rinehart accepted a position with the Veterans' Bureau. There, Rinehart continued to write and also became involved in Washington society, hosting and being hosted by presidents, senators, and ambassadors. In summer the family traveled to their cabin at Eatons' Ranch in Wyoming, a part of the country that Mary fell in love with after being invited to join a horse packing expedition out west in 1916. In 1929 her sons Stan and Ted, along with John Farrar, launched Farrar & Rinehart Publishing Company, which would publish many of her works. Dr. Rinehart died in 1931 after a period of poor health. A few years later, Rinehart relocated to New York City, where she would be closer to her sons and their growing families. In 1937 she purchased a large house in Bar Harbor, Maine, and spent summers there until 1947 when her house burned down in a large fire. Rinehart died in 1958 in New York City at the age of 83. She experienced several episodes of poor health during her life, including breast cancer and coronary thrombosis. Despite this, she lived an active, busy life filled with writing, travel, family, and other pursuits.
More detailed information about Mary Roberts Rinehart's life can be found in her autobiography My Story, published in 1931, and My Story: A New Edition and Seventeen New Years (1948), as well as in Improbable Fiction: The Life of Mary Roberts Rinehart by Jan Cohn (1980).
Scope and Content Notes
The Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers primarily document the writing, publishing, and producing of her literary and dramatic works. They include manuscripts and notes, contracts with publishers and producers, proofs, correspondence with editors and readers, illustrations, and published works, as well as pens and other tools she used in her writing. A variety of items in several series relate to Rinehart's travels and writing in Europe during World War I. Rinehart's family, her travels, and her homes in Glen Osborne, Pennsylvania, Washington, D.C., Eaton's Ranch, Wyoming, and Bar Harbor, Maine, are also represented in the collection, primarily in correspondence and photographs.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into eight series:
Series I. Personal Documents and Ephemera, 1831-1956
Series II. Manuscripts and Notes, 1907-1994
Series III. Proofs, circa 1933-1957
Series IV. Published Works, 1904-1983
Series V. Contracts and Business Records, 1906-1962
Series VI. Correspondence, 1912-1958
Series VII. Photographs and Artwork, 1875-circa 1948
Series VIII. Realia, 1918-1953
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the University of Pittsburgh by Mary Roberts Rinehart's sons after her death in 1958.
Previous Citation
Mary Roberts Rinehart Papers, 1831-1970, SC.1958.03, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Realia; Manuscripts (Document genre); Works of art; World War, 1914-1918 -- Fiction; Detective and mystery stories; Detective and mystery stories, American; Physicians -- Fiction; Medical fiction, American; Detective and mystery stories, American -- Women authors; Women authors, American -- 20th century; World War, 1914-1918 -- Personal narratives; World War, 1914-1918 -- Press coverage -- United States; Manuscripts for publication; Financial records; Correspondence; Photographs; Women; Personal papers; Rinehart & Company, Inc; Farrar & Rinehart; Rinehart, Mary Roberts; Rinehart, Stanley Marshall
- Personal Documents and Ephemera, 1831-1956; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains personal documents, travel documents, awards, family papers, and ephemera collected by Mary Roberts Rinehart. Some of the items are from her travels in Europe during World War I.
  - Rinehart, Wm. - The Remembrance - 1830, 1831-1837 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rinehart family - personal papers, circa 1840, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hahnemann Medical College - receipts for S.M. Rinehart, 1889-1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cheer Up program, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trade [U.K.] - Notices to Mariners. For "Foreign-going Ships", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campagne de 1914, Ruines d'Ypres - postcards (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - German documents - prayer / hymn booklet for German soldiers and postcard to a German soldier, 1897, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mary Roberts Rinehart's travels in Europe during World War I - menus and other ephemera, 1915, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Democratic National Convention - press ticket - St. Louis, Missouri, June 14, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - U.S. Department of State - special passport for Mary Roberts Rinehart, October 21, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Palisades Manufacturing Company - The Army Doctor in War: His Duties and His Heroism (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: "CP Diary", 1918; 16. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Recovered from observation post during Mary Roberts Rinehart's tour of battle fields in France days after the end of World War I. Referenced in chapter 38 of My Story by Mary Roberts Rinehart.
  - Edgar Allen Poe Award and Pennsylvania Ambassador Citation, 1949, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Department of State - passport issued to Rinehart family to travel to the West Indies and Central and South America, January 21, 1916 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - U.S. War Office - commission of Stanley Marshall Rinehart to Officers' Reserve Corps of the Army of the United States, August 4, 1917 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Hahnemann Medical College - diploma of Stanley M. Rinehart, 1891 (Map-case 1, Drawer 7)
- Manuscripts and Notes, 1907-1994; II.
  This series contains manuscripts of works by Mary Roberts Rinehart. Many of the documents are typescripts; some are handwritten. In some manuscripts, parts of pages are pinned to other pages with straight pins. Pins have been left in place to preserve the edited forms of the manuscripts. Also in this series are notes and notebooks related to Mary Roberts Rinehart's writing. In addition to works by Mary Roberts Rinehart, this series contains manuscripts of adaptations of Mary Roberts Rinehart's works by others. Some folders of notes also contain documents written by people other than Rinehart.
  Folders are in alphabetical order by title of work, or by subject in the absence of a title. For manuscripts in which the published title is known and is different from the title on the manuscript, the published title is used, with the draft title noted as an alternate title in the scope and content notes for the folder. Larger manuscripts are in alphabetical order in legal-sized document boxes at the end of the series. Notebooks are housed in the last box of the series.
  - "America - 1941" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Are Our Women Slackers?", circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Are You Voting This Year?" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Avenger. A One Act Play by Mary Roberts Rinehart and Stanley Marshall Rinehart (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Bar Harbor - Before and After", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Bat-A Play of Mystery in Three Acts by Mary Roberts Rinehart and Avery Hopwood-copy 1, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Original folder note: "as revised by Mary Roberts Rinehart in 1945."
  - The Bat - A Play of Mystery in Three Acts by Mary Roberts Rinehart and Avery Hopwood - copy 2, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Bat - new adaptation and screenplay by Crane Wilbur (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Bat - adapted for television by Walter Kerr, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    For "The Dow Hour of Great Mysteries"
  - "Before the Drums Beat", 1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Behind the Scenes with the Charity Ball" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Being a 'Good Scout,'", circa 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "'Bob' Davis" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Breaking Point, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Building a Marriage", circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "A Cake for Mr. Hitler: A Tish Story", 1941 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Can Women Stop Crime?", 1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Capital Punishment" (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The Country's Stepchildren", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dangerous Days scenario, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Continuity by Charles Kenyon.
  - "Dear Mr. President" (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Dinner for the Ambassador" (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Door That Would Not Stay Closed", 1941 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Dorothy Dresses for Dinner", 1941 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Drama in Everyday Living", circa 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The Fallacy of Freedom", 1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Family Pays the Bill", circa 1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "The Girl Who Hated to Fish" (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "God's Fool" scenario, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Continuity by J.G. Hawks.
  - "Going Back" and other articles (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Hazard", circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    "Hazard" is the published title. Alternate titles include "Dog-sitter," "One Snowy Night."
  - "The Hero" and "The Tragedy" - notes, circa 1928 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "I Speak for Wives", circa 1937 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Alternate title: "The Case for Wives."
  - "If I Had a Daughter" (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "If Only It Were Yesterday", circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Alternate title: "The Perfect Alibi"
  - "The Increasing Repute of the Crime Story", 1930 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "The Inside Story" (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Lark - original motion picture scenario, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "The Little Lamp", 1913 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "A Lodge in Some Vast Wildnerness", 1929 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "Looking for the Magic Word", 1934 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "The Mad Hatter's Tea Party" (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "The Man Upstairs", circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Marian's Ghost", 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "The Medical Quick Lunch Counter", 1913 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "The Missing Make-up" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Mr. Caswell Looks Out the Window", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Mrs. Forsyth and the Milkman", circa 1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "My America", 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "My Country, Right or Left, My Country", 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "A New First Lady Becomes Hostess for the Nation", 1929 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Draft title: "A New First Lady Enters The White House."
  - "One Night in Spring", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "The origin of 'The Dog in the Orchard'", 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Our House", 1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Passing the Theatrical Buck", 1929 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "The Pattern", 1941 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "The Philanderer's Wife", 1938 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Power and Glory - [book review], 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "The Right to Live", 1947 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Roses (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Saturday Evening Post piece (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "The Scandal", 1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "The Second Marriage", 1935 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "The Secret", 1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Sidney's Wife", 1906-1908 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Sophie Kerr" (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "The Splinter", 1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Draft title: "The Empty Room."
  - "The Splinter" (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Draft title: "The Splinter Clue."
  - "Spreading Christmas Through the Year", 1935 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Strange Journey: A Tish Story", 1936 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "The Street of Seven Stars"-user copy, pages 1-201, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "The Street of Seven Stars"-user photocopy, pages 202-428, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "The Street of Seven Stars"-user photocopy, pages 440-595, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "The Striking Storks", 1907 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Suffrage and voting (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Taking the Cure in Europe", 1932 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Tall Tree", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Thoughts" column, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 7-10)
    Collection of short pieces, some of which were published in Mary Roberts Rinehart's "Thoughts" column in Ladies' Home Journal, circa 1931-32.
  - Three Weeks by Elinor Glyn - [book review], circa 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Tish Disposes of a Body: a Tish Story" (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tish-film adaptation by Annalee Whitmore and Thomas Seller, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "To Mother, With Love" (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Tomb of the Unknown Soldier (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Two Clues to Murder" (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "The Uselessness of Fear", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Washington Naval Conference pieces (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Folder contains "New Ways for Old: War Has Ceased to Be a Profitable Business."
  - Washington Naval Conference pieces (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Folder contains "The End of the Pageant."
  - Washington Naval Conference pieces (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Folder contains "The Evidence Against Japan" and "A Liability or an Asset: Which is Japan to Be?"
  - Washington novel - notes (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Includes manuscript: "Confessions of a Congressman as told to Oliver P. Newman."
  - "The Street of Seven Stars" (Box 5A, Folder 1-3)
    Restricted use: very fragile holograph original. See user photocopy in this series.
  - "Welcome Home: A Christmas Story", 1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Who Will be Nominated?", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Draft title: "Since I Lost My Vote."
  - "Willkie Campaign 1940" (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Women on a Dude Ranch", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "The Worst Job in the World", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Draft title: "The Human Side of the Presidency." Folder includes letter from The White House.
  - "The Young Visitor", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Your America, and Mine", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Your Child and the Movies", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "The Burned Chair", circa 1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Folder includes memorandum with comments on manuscript.
  - "The Frightened Wife", 1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Great House" (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "I Want an Island" (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "The Lighted Candle", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Folder includes author's proofs.
  - "The Little Red Book", circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "The Love Affairs of a Freak", 1906 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Night of the Party" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Parole Refused", 1951 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Poems and stories (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Some are fragile. Titles include "Moving Day," "The Cat at the Dog Show," "The Paces of Pegasus," "The Mother Tree," "To My Mirror," "The Tragedy of a Tatooed Man," "The New Union," "In De Full O' De Moon," "Lilies for Peace," and "Out on the Hills Away."
  - "The Poisoned Pigeons" - copy 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Alternate title: "The Dead Pigeons." Typescript and holograph, with pins.
  - "The Poisoned Pigeons" - copy 2 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Alternate title: "The Dead Pigeons." Typescript.
  - The Spider: A Play in One Act (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "A Time for Living" (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "To My Boys" (Box 8, Folder 2)
    This manuscript of Rinehart's life story was intended for her sons. The content of this hand-written document differs from her published autobiography My Story. The original manuscript is not located in the collection. However, there is a preservation facsimile available for researcher use.
  - "To My Boys"-typed transcription prepared by Charlotte Macleod, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Untitled short story (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - World War I notes (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - World War I notes-diary of a German officer killed at the Yser, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    English translation is included in "No Man's Land" by Mary Roberts Rinehart, published as a magazine article and as chapter 9 of Kings, Queens and Pawns.
  - World War I notes - meeting with Albert I, King of the Belgians (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Forms the basis of "A Talk With the King of the Belgians" by Mary Roberts Rinehart, published as a magazine article and as chapter 5 of the book Kings, Queens and Pawns. Folder includes envelope given to Mary Roberts Rinehart by King Albert to write on when she interviewed him; the envelope is referenced in chapter 26 of her autobiography My Story.
  - World War I notes - report draft (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - World War I notes - report notes and draft (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - World War I notebook - The Business Year Book, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - World War I notebook - note pad with cover missing (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - World War I notebook - Reporters' Note Book (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - World War I notebook - Letts's Notebook No. 12 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Notes for stories - 240 Page Composition Book (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Time for Living" and other notes - brown notebook with black tape binding (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - U.S. presidency notes - 2 notepads - Scratch Book, No. 4026 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Autobiographical notes - Pocket Notes Memo Book (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Autobiographical notes - brown spiral-bound notebook (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Proofs, circa 1933-1957; III.
  This series contains galley proofs and plate proofs of stories and books by Mary Roberts Rinehart. Folders are in alphabetical order by title of work.
  - "The Inside Story", 1934 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "The Little General" (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Mary Roberts Rinehart Crime Book-front matter design sheets, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Mary Roberts Rinehart Crime Book-galley proofs, front matter and pages 1-199, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Mary Roberts Rinehart Crime Book-plate proofs-front matter to page 200-505, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Mary Roberts Rinehart Crime Book-plate proofs-pages 1-200, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Mary Roberts Rinehart Crime Book-plate proofs-pages 201-505, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Mouse: A Tish Story" (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The State versus Elinor Norton, circa 1933 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "Those That Wait" (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Tish Goes to Jail" (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "The Uselessness of Fear" (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Published Works, 1904-1983; IV.
  This series contains published works by and about Mary Roberts Rinehart. Most items are clippings from magazines; the series also includes booklets and issues of magazines.
  - Works by Mary Roberts Rinehart, 1904-1983; 1.
    This subseries contains published works written by Mary Roberts Rinehart. Works include romance and crime stories, commentaries and opinion pieces, and autobiographical sketches and travel articles. Clippings are primarily from magazines, including The Saturday Evening Post, Hearst's International - Cosmopolitan, Harper's Bazaar, Good Housekeeping, Ladies' Home Journal, Munsey's Magazine, All-Story Magazine, and The American Magazine. Also in this series are two scrapbooks containing clippings of Mary Roberts Rinehart's early published works.
    Works are in alphabetical order by title, primarily grouped in folders by first letter of title. Longer serial works and magazine issues are in their own folders with the full title of the work, in alphabetical order with the other folders. Larger items are in alphabetical order by title of work in an oversize box, Box 32.
    - A, 1907-1941 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - B, 1914-1943 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - C, 1906-1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Case is Closed", 1951 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Code No. 31" in The Saturday Evening Post vol. 225 no. 4-5, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - D, 1912-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - E, 1930-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - F, 1908-1953 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Four A.M.", 1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - G, 1910-1932 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "The Great Mistake", 1940 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - H, 1908-1950 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - I-J, 1909-1950 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - L, 1907-1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - M, 1908-1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Mary Roberts Rinehart: A Sketch of the Woman and Her Work (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Includes "My Creed" and "The Detective Story" by Mary Roberts Rinehart and articles by Grant Overton about Mary Roberts Rinehart and her work.
    - "Mary Roberts Rinehart Shows How Truth is Stranger Than Fiction" - user photocopies (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Promotional piece about "The After House." Oversize original is in Map Case 1 Drawer 7 in Special Collections Department.
    - "Miss Pinkerton", 1932 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "My Story", 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "The Woman Who Was Myself", 1930-1931 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Excerpts from "My Story." Includes "Mary Roberts Rinehart's Place in American Fiction" by Grant Overton and a bibliography.
    - N, 1926-1929 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - O, 1916-1944 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - P, 1907-1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Q-R, 1908-1926 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - S, 1907-1950 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Ta-Th, 1910-1953 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "Nat i storbyen" ["That is All"] in Uge-Revyen Nr. 43, 44, 45. 11 Argang, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Thoughts" column, circa 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Collection of short pieces for Mary Roberts Rinehart's "Thoughts" column in Ladies' Home Journal. Most columns have the heading "Thoughts," with subheadings for individual articles within. Other titles of the column include "Put Your Money to Work And Other Thoughts" and "What We Do With Our Tax Money And Other Thoughts."
    - To-Tw, 1906-1943 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Twenty-three and a Half Hours' Leave" - shorthand - in The Gregg Writer vol XLIV no. 8, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Issue also includes "From History to Mysteries" by Lawrence David Brennan about Mary Roberts Rinehart's secretary, William Sladen.
    - "Two Army Christmases" in U.S. Army Recruiting News vol. 2 no. 52, December 25, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Two Flights Up", 1926 (Box 14, Folder 6)